<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>CoopExtraHUD</name>
    <directory>coopextrahud</directory>
    <id>3502047453</id>
    <description>**CoopExtraHUD** enhances the co-op experience in *The Binding of Isaac: Repentance+* by showing each player's passive collectibles in a clean, minimal grid HUD on the right side of your screen.

Choose between two HUD styles:

- **Updated Preset:** Centered vertically along the right edge for balanced, easy viewing.  
- **Vanilla+ Preset:** Right-justified just below the map area, keeping that classic feel.

The HUD dynamically scales with the number of players and items, plus you can customize nearly everything — scale, opacity, spacing, offsets, divider lines, and more — all in-game via the Mod Config Menu (MCM).

---

## Features (Working)

- **Multi-Player Support:** Displays passive items for all co-op players, including multiplayer and new player joins
- **Modded Item Support:** Full compatibility with modded collectibles, automatically detects and displays items from mods
- **True Pickup Order:** Tracks and displays collectibles in actual pickup order per player
- **Dual HUD Modes:** Two preset layouts with different positioning and visual styles
- **Smart Scaling:** Auto-scaling for different screen sizes, item counts, and resolutions
- **Full Customization:** Adjustable scale, opacity, spacing, offsets, divider positioning, and more
- **Per-Preset Reset:** Instantly reset all display settings to defaults for the current HUD mode
- **Auto-Adjust on Resize:** Option to keep HUD position relative when resizing the game window
- **Minimap Auto-Align:** One-click button to snap minimap to top-right and avoid overlap
- **Debug Overlay:** Toggleable overlay for visualizing HUD, boundaries, and minimap areas
- **Jacob &amp; Esau Combo Block Tuning:** Fine-tune divider offsets, chunk gaps, and scale for J&amp;E's shared HUD block
- **Visual Helpers:** Automatic overlay guides when adjusting settings (red=boundary, cyan=minimap, green=HUD position)
- **Minimap Avoidance:** Intelligent positioning to avoid overlapping with minimap areas
- **Preset Management:** Save/load custom settings separately for each HUD mode with reset options
- **Performance Optimized:** Efficient caching system with minimal frame-by-frame overhead
- **Enhanced MCM Integration:** Full MCM support with smart overlay helpers that automatically appear when hovering over relevant settings
- **Intelligent Overlay System:** Context-aware visual guides show exactly what each setting affects (HUD Position, Boundaries, Minimap areas)
- **Real-Time Preview:** All changes instantly visible with automatic overlay detection based on current MCM tab
- **Manual Controls:** Keyboard shortcuts (B/M/H/N keys) for quick overlay toggling

---

## Work in Progress / Planned

- **Additional Presets:** More HUD layouts and positioning options (e.g., 2-above-2-below, grid, etc.)
- **Enhanced Scaling:** Better support for unusual screen setups and ultra-wide displays
- **Advanced Customization:** Per-player color coding and additional visual options

---

## Controls

**Automatic Overlays (MCM):**
- Navigate to **HUD** tab to see HUD position helpers (green corners)
- Navigate to **Boundaries** tab to see boundary helpers (red corners)  
- Navigate to **Minimap** tab to see minimap area helpers (cyan corners)
- Overlays automatically appear when hovering over relevant settings

**Manual Overlays (Keyboard):**
- **B** - Toggle boundary overlay (red corners)
- **M** - Toggle minimap overlay (cyan corners)  
- **H** - Toggle HUD position overlay (green corners)
- **N** - Clear all overlays

---

Perfect for streamers, couch co-op players, or anyone wanting clearer HUD info during hectic runs!</description>
    <version>1.1.6</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
